<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Portfolio website for Yi Yan Ng</title>
    <link>https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Portfolio website for Yi Yan Ng</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A look into ferility in different countries</title>
      <link>https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/fertility/fertilitymortality/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/fertility/fertilitymortality/</guid>
      <description>Fertility in different countriesIn the following section of the report we analyze demographic data across countries sourced from the World Bank, specifically we will look at data on:
Life expectancy at birth (life_expectancy_years.csv)GDP per capita in constant 2010 US$ (https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/NY.GDP.PCAP.KD)Female fertility: The number of babies per woman (https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SP.DYN.TFRT.IN)Primary school enrollment as % of children attending primary school (https://data.worldbank.org/indicator/SE.PRM.NENR)Mortality rate, for under 5, per 1000 live births (https://data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predicting AirBnB Prices in Singapore</title>
      <link>https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/airbnbsg/finalsingaporeproject/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/airbnbsg/finalsingaporeproject/</guid>
      <description>Executive SummaryIn this report we will be analysing data about Airbnb listings in Singapore with the goal of building a model to predict the total cost for two people staying four nights in Singapore. The data is from insideairbnb.com
Purpose &amp;amp; Scope: the purpose of this report is to elucidate upon the set deliverable across five facets:
Perform a cohesive exploratory data analysis;Chart data in plots and geospatial format to discern trends and select explanatory variables for regression purposes;Conduct a robust regression analysis with selected variables;Diagnose variables demonstrating collinearity, replace said variables to curtail “Variance Inflation Factor”, summarize shortlisted data sets for predictive and informative purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session 6: Homework 3</title>
      <link>https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/gdpcountries/gdpsection/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/gdpcountries/gdpsection/</guid>
      <description>GDP components over time and among countriesThe GDP data we will look at is from the United Nations’ National Accounts Main Aggregates Database, which contains estimates of total GDP and its components for all countries from 1970 to today. We will look at how GDP and its components have changed over time, and compare different countries and how much each component contributes to that country’s GDP. At the risk of oversimplifying things, the main components of gross domestic product, GDP are personal consumption (C), business investment (I), government spending (G) and net exports (exports - imports).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Session 6: Homework 3</title>
      <link>https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/movies/movies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://yiyan-portfolio.netlify.app/projects/movies/movies/</guid>
      <description>Steven Spielberg bs Tim BurtonFor this analysis, we would like to analyze the differences in rating between Steven Spielberg and Tim Burton. Using the IMBD ratings data, we explore whether the mean IMDB rating for Steven Spielberg and Tim Burton are the same or not. We calculate the confidence intervals for the mean ratings of these two directors and as you can see they overlap.
movies &amp;lt;- read_csv(here::here(&amp;quot;content/projects/movies/data&amp;quot;, &amp;quot;movies.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
